<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-03-09T18:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Set Up HTTPS for Free on a Dockerized Ruby on Rails Production Server</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2019/03/09/production-https-setup-for-ruby-on-rails-app-with-docker.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2019/03/09/production-https-setup-for-ruby-on-rails-app-with-docker.html</id>
    <published>2019-03-09T18:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-09T20:13:14-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently launched a Ruby on Rails based application and wanted to add HTTPS to my domain. In this
post, I&amp;#39;m going to show you how to add HTTPS to your domain using a tool called Certbot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why do you need HTTPS?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTTPS is an essential service for modern web applications. An HTTPS-enabled website will encrypt all of the data
sent between you and the website server. This protects your passwords and other sensitive information from
third parties on the Internet such as other users on your local Wifi network. HTTPS can also be used as a means
to help users identify that they are on a correct website and not a scam website doctored to look like an authentic
website. With the major web browsers like Chrome now labeling non-HTTPS enabled websites as insecure, HTTPS may soon
be a required feature for website delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="images/2019/Screen%20Shot%202019-02-23%20at%2010.45.25%20PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="../../../images/2019/ScreenShot2019-02-23at10.45.25PM.png" alt="Screen shot 2019 02 23 at 10.45.25 pm" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Example of how an HTTPS enabled site displays
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="images/2019/Screen%20Shot%202019-02-23%20at%2010.48.14%20PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="../../../images/2019/ScreenShot2019-02-23at10.48.14PM.png" alt="Screen shot 2019 02 23 at 10.48.14 pm" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Example of how a not-HTTPS enabled site is displayed (as insecure)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular HTTPS setup is making several assumptions on your general website setup. In this case I had the
following pieces of software already running and configured:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu Linux 18.04 (Bionic Beaver) - this won&amp;#39;t work for Heroku or Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application running on Docker

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rails app already installed on the server via Capistrano and running via Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NGINX installed on the server (but you can also run it via a Docker container)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certbot installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What is NGINX?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NGINX is a Node.js based web server. In the Javascript world it can be used similarly to WEBRICK, Puma, or Thin
of the Ruby world. You could whole Javacsript applications served by NGINX. It&amp;#39;s also known for it&amp;#39;s speed, which
has similar performance benchmarks to Apache HTTP Server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example NGINX serves three functions:
1) Integrate our HTTPS certificate into transport layer.
2) Redirect traffic seeking the HTTP port 80 to the HTTPS port 443 to force clients into using the more secure protocol.
3) Route web traffic to the appropriate container for the domain name of the request. This will allow us to serve
   multiple websites using the same Linux server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of setup for routing web traffic is called a reverse-proxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="images/2019/Screen%20Shot%202019-02-24%20at%202.12.21%20PM.png"&gt;&lt;img src="../../../images/2019/ScreenShot2019-02-24at2.12.21PM.png" alt="Screen shot 2019 02 24 at 2.12.21 pm" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      How the NGINX reverse proxy routes traffic to the appropriate application port based on the domain
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;How do you install NGINX?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation instructions are found on &lt;a href="https://www.nginx.com/resources/wiki/start/topics/tutorials/install/"&gt;the official NGINX website&lt;/a&gt;.
For this example instance, I installed NGINX using the &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt; repository:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="bash"&gt;$ sudo apt-get install nginx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it&amp;#39;s installed, a useful command to run is the configuration test, which verifies the OK status of its configuration
settings.
&lt;code&gt;
$ sudo nginx -T
nginx: the configuration file /etc/nginx/nginx.conf syntax is ok
nginx: configuration file /etc/nginx/nginx.conf test is successful
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What is Let&amp;#39;s Encrypt and Certbot?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s Encrypt is a nonprofit organization that promises to be the Internet&amp;#39;s free, automated, and open Certficate
Authority (CA). Several companies such as Symantec, DigiCert, GoDaddy are also CA&amp;#39;s and offer certificates for a fee.
For HTTPS to work, your server needs to install a certificate from one of these companies, which is nothing more
than a private encryption key associated with your domain. When a client connects to your website, your server will send
a message encrypted with that private key, which can be decoded by a public key on the client&amp;#39;s end. HTTPS enabled web
browsers like Firefox or Chrome come with these public keys preinstalled, per an arrangement with the CA companies.
If you want a more general overview of how HTTPS certificates work, here is a great &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iQsKdtjwtYI"&gt;YouTube video&lt;/a&gt;
explaining the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s Encrypt has made the installation and renewal of SSL Certificates easy with a tool called &lt;a href="https://github.com/certbot/certbot"&gt;Certbot&lt;/a&gt;.
Certbot validates your server to the Let&amp;#39;s Encrypt by having it perform what it calls an ACME &lt;a href="https://certbot.eff.org/docs/challenges.html?highlight=http"&gt;challenge&lt;/a&gt;.
An example would be when you run Certbot, it will make a temporary file available via HTTP which the Let&amp;#39;s Encrypt
organization can access. Let&amp;#39;s Encrypt will then check the DNS records to verify that the domain name you want to
certify points to the server you are running Certbot from. If the DNS matches, then Let&amp;#39;s Encrypt will send
a newly issued certificate to your Certbot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Certbot Tnstallation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installation instructions are available on the &lt;a href="https://certbot.eff.org/docs/install.html"&gt;Certbot user guides&lt;/a&gt;, but
here is a summary of the commands I used to install Certbot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="bash"&gt;$ sudo apt-get update
$ sudo apt-get install software-properties-common
$ sudo add-apt-repository universe
$ sudo add-apt-repository ppa:certbot/certbot
$ sudo apt-get update
$ sudo apt-get install certbot python-certbot-nginx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that I also installed the &lt;code&gt;python-certbot-nginx&lt;/code&gt; module, which invokes our instance of NGINX in performing
the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Configure the DNS to Point to the Server&amp;#39;s IP Address&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need is an A or CNAME record pointing your domain to the IP address of your Linux server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Run the Certbot ACME Challenge to Verify the Domain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo certbot --nginx -d my-example-domain.com -d www.my-example-domain.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passing the &lt;code&gt;nginx&lt;/code&gt; flag tells Certbot to use NGINX to perform the ACME challenge. Certbot temporarily modifies the
NGINX settings so that the remote Let&amp;#39;s Encrypt system can find a file on your system to complete the challenge.
Once complete, it will automatically install the received SSL certificate, which will act as a private key during the HTTPS initiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Update the NGINX settings to forward HTTP to HTTPS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certbot should update your NGINX settings automatically, but here&amp;#39;s now it will look after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# /etc/nginx/sites-available/my-example-domain.com

server {
    root /var/www/my-example-domain.com/current/public; # Directly serves anything in the Rails public folder
    index index.html index.htm index.nginx-debian.html;
    server_name my-example-domain.com www.my-example-domain.com; # managed by Certbot

    location / {
        proxy_pass http://localhost:8030; # 8030 is the port the Docker container is running on
          proxy_set_header Host $host;
          #try_files $uri $uri/ =404;
    }

    listen [::]:443 ssl ipv6only=on; # managed by Certbot
    listen 443 ssl; # managed by Certbot
    ssl_certificate /etc/letsencrypt/live/my-example-domain.com/fullchain.pem; # managed by Certbot
    ssl_certificate_key /etc/letsencrypt/live/my-example-domain.com/privkey.pem; # managed by Certbot
    include /etc/letsencrypt/options-ssl-nginx.conf; # managed by Certbot
    ssl_dhparam /etc/letsencrypt/ssl-dhparams.pem; # managed by Certbot
}

server {
    if ($host = www.my-example-domain.com) {
        return 301 https://$host$request_uri;
    } # managed by Certbot


    if ($host = my-example-domain.com) {
        return 301 https://$host$request_uri;
    } # managed by Certbot

    listen 80 ;
    listen [::]:80 ;
    server_name my-example-domain.com www.my-example-domain.com;
    return 404; # managed by Certbot
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NGINX has two important folders for domain settings:
&lt;code&gt;/etc/nginx/sites-available&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;/etc/nginx/sites-enabled&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;sites-available&lt;/code&gt; folder has the NGINX proxy settings for each individual website. The &lt;code&gt;sites-enabled&lt;/code&gt; should
contain symlinks to the files in the &lt;code&gt;sites-available&lt;/code&gt; folder. Create a symlink at the command line like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ln -s /etc/nginx/sites-enabled/my-example-domain.com /etc/nginx/sites-available/my-example-domain.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional Resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://blog.heckel.xyz/2013/07/01/how-to-use-mitmproxy-to-read-and-modify-https-traffic-of-your-phone/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iQsKdtjwtYI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to connect a Docker application to a Postgres database on the host machine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2019/02/05/how-to-connect-docker-to-a-postgres-database-on-host-machine-localhost.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2019/02/05/how-to-connect-docker-to-a-postgres-database-on-host-machine-localhost.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-05T01:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-09T19:14:19-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Connecting a Docker application to non-Dockerized Postgres database from is a more complicated task
than you would think. While a Docker container can easily communicate with other containers running on the same machine,
it can&amp;#39;t easily find how to connect to the host machine running it. This is because of the way Docker handles 
networking, by isolating the containers on its own virtual network which doesn&amp;#39;t include the computer hosting Docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while back I published &lt;a href="2017-06-01-connecting-to-external-postgres-database-with-docker.html.markdown"&gt;How to connect to an external Postgres database from a Docker container&lt;/a&gt;,
which showed you how to tinker with the settings on your local machine or any other computer in your local network
so that your Dockerized app can connect to Postgres. I&amp;#39;ve recently discovered an alternative method which is even faster.
Here&amp;#39;s how I do it now: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="yaml"&gt;version: &amp;#39;3&amp;#39;

services:
  myapp:
    build: .
    command: &amp;quot;bundle exec rails s&amp;quot;
    environment:
      - DATABASE_URL=${DATABASE_URL} # Connection string to the database goes here
      - PGPASSWORD=${PGPASSWORD}
      - RAILS_ENV=${RAILS_ENV:-development}
      - RAILS_LOG_TO_STDOUT=true
    network_mode: host
    tty: true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice how in my &lt;code&gt;docker-compose&lt;/code&gt; the &lt;code&gt;network_mode&lt;/code&gt; is &amp;quot;host&amp;quot;. This value will cause the container to run from the
host&amp;#39;s network directly - no isolation of the container onto its own network. That means &lt;code&gt;localhost&lt;/code&gt; in the container
will point to the &lt;code&gt;localhost&lt;/code&gt; of your machine. You can then connect to Postgres in the command line from within
the container like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ docker-compose run myapp /bin/sh

/app # psql -U postgres -h localhost
psql (10.5, server 9.6.11)
Type &amp;quot;help&amp;quot; for help.

postgres=# 

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that it&amp;#39;s necessary to specify the &lt;code&gt;-h localhost&lt;/code&gt; parameter. Also, if you make use of the &lt;code&gt;PGPASSWORD&lt;/code&gt; environment
variable you can have that set to the database password so that it won&amp;#39;t prompt you to type it in.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Three Allergic Triggers That Can Cause Eczema</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2019/02/04/three-allergic-triggers-that-can-cause-eczema.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2019/02/04/three-allergic-triggers-that-can-cause-eczema.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-04T18:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2019-03-09T19:11:53-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Part 2: How Allergic Reactions and Eczema Are Related&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I discussed in &lt;a href="../03/i-conquered-eczema-after-30-years-of-itchy-skin-and-you-can-too.html"&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; of this blog post series, there is an immune system and allergic reaction component to eczema.
As someone who has dealt with quite severe eczema my whole life, I can confirm that allergies have a lot to do
with it per my own experimentation with exposure and avoidance of certain triggers. In some respects, eczema sufferers
are just people who are hypersensitive to environmental allergens. Eliminate the allergens, and the problem goes away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way your body produces inflammation is complex. I find that most educational resources that describe the process go
into a lot of detail on the specific chemical interactions, which makes it hard to understand. But I think a key
takeaway about inflammation in regard to allergy is that it can turn into a perpetual chain reaction like a nuclear
reactor or a flame burning through fuel. A few of your cells identify a foreign substance in your skin that shouldn&amp;#39;t
be there, so those cells respond by releasing antibodies and other chemicals to fight the invader. But these same
chemicals also trigger other cells to start doing the same and produce even more of these immune response proteins. Soon, the entire
area of skin is producing these chemicals and the inflammatory reaction spreads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cdCh4_Ckor0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of an allergy, your body is reacting to a benign environmental substance like cat saliva proteins for example,
which it&amp;#39;s trying to purge like it would a virus or bacteria. Once this process gets going it could keep itself going
and you have a rash long after you&amp;#39;ve been exposed to the allergen. It is at this point that your doctor may say it&amp;#39;s
necessary to &amp;quot;calm it down&amp;quot; with the use of a topical drug. The video below describes how the drug Eucrisa is thought
to work. It interferes in this reaction, blocking some of the immune system signaling proteins, and thereby stopping
the chain reaction of inflammation. Basically most drugs used to treat inflammatory response work similarly by
interfering somewhere along the chain of chemical reactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;video src="videos/2019/PFEU7008000H_Eucrisa_DTC_MOA-5575791536001.mp4" style="width: 640px;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although drugs may be necessary sometimes to calm eczema down, I find that the best way of staying healthy is to avoid
allergy triggers altogether. Sometimes it is difficult to pin down your specific allergic triggers as every person&amp;#39;s
case is different. I hope this brief list gives you clues on where to begin experimenting to find your own triggers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Shampoos, soaps, and other personal care products that contact your skin&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my early 20s around the time I met my future wife, I started getting a really bad series of eczema outbreaks all
along my arms. My left arm especially was covered in itchy red rashes. I went to multiple doctors, and got the usual
treatment of triamcinolone, which only worked briefly before the rashes ripped right back. They tried more powerful
creams like fluocinonide and the problem kept getting worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;#39;t until one dermatologist I visited noticed that the rash on my wrist seem to fall in a perfectly straight line.
She asked me what I do that I might be rubbing against something causing me an allergy. She told a story of another
patient with a similar case of hand eczema, and they figured out that that patient had an allergy to the chemicals in
money and it was the way she would hold dollar bills that caused the rashes on her hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After much thinking, we suspected that the rash on my wrist might be from the way I would play with my wife&amp;#39;s
hair when we&amp;#39;re walking around the streets of Chicago on our dates. We scrutinized her shampoo. A patch test confirmed
that I was allergic to Pantene. My dermatologist said that shampoo allergies are actually a common thing people end up
getting treated for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="image-box"&gt;
  &lt;div class="image-box-content"&gt;
    &lt;a href="../../../images/2019/right-hand-wrist-eczema.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="../../../images/2019/right-hand-wrist-eczema.jpg" alt="Right hand wrist eczema" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-box-caption"&gt;
      Dermatitis rash on my wrist with a well defined line at the allergen point of contact
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years we&amp;#39;ve experimented with several shampoos to see what I&amp;#39;m allergic to. I&amp;#39;ve switched to the Free and Clear
brand of shampoo, which is supposed to not contain a lot of the toxic ingredients of the big brand shampoos. The common
ingredient that I could find causing me trouble is &lt;strong&gt;cocamide DEA&lt;/strong&gt;, an agent used to help the shampoo produce those
frothy bubbles when you rub it in your hair. I&amp;#39;m not 100% certain if that&amp;#39;s the only problematic ingredient, but it does
seem to have a correlation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Allergies to dogs and cats&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve known since I was a kid that cats in proximity cause me to have watery eyes and a stuffy nose. But it was only
in recent years that I learned they can cause me dermatitis outbreaks as well. On a prick test when I was 23, I was told
that I had an affirmative reaction to both dog and cat proteins. Several years later I decided to fight through
my allergy and tried petting a cat that approached me. After a few minutes, my arm broke out in hives and in the
following days I got a pretty nasty dermatitis rash. It didn&amp;#39;t kill me, but it didn&amp;#39;t make me stronger either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More sneaky is my allergy to dogs. I really like dogs, but unfortunately I can&amp;#39;t interact with them a whole lot without
getting a dermatitis rash. I say it&amp;#39;s sneaky because I&amp;#39;ve figured out that when I pet a dog, the rashes don&amp;#39;t manifest
until at least a day or two later. Wearing disposable plastic gloves seems to work in preventing the rashes if I want
to pet a dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Food allergies&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A less examined link between chronic eczema and allergens is food allergy. Allergens you ingest could manifest as a skin
rash, making it very difficult to see the link. However, there&amp;#39;s a growing body of scientific evidence demonstrating this,
such as &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2923958/"&gt;this case study by the NIH&lt;/a&gt; showing a link between
patients who suffered from dematitis rashes and the consumption of nickel in their diet. Nickel is often absorbed
through whole grain breads and oatmeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case I discovered that I have an allergy to coconut. I really like the taste of coconut, so was shocked when I
figured this out, but it makes sense since it could be related to my allergic reaction to cocamide DEA in shampoos.
I first started suspecting this when I noticed that the sweat I&amp;#39;d get during workouts seemed to cause a lot of itching
and later dermatitis around my neck. It was hard to deal with because I didn&amp;#39;t know exactly what to do about it. It
steadily became more of a problem over a 2 year period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started to wonder what if there&amp;#39;s something &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; my sweat that was causing the problem, like a food I&amp;#39;ve been eating
that&amp;#39;s getting sweat out during the exercise. What have I been doing differently lately that it&amp;#39;s becoming more of a
problem than before? I started making pre-workout smoothies with coconut water and various fruits. So I tested this
out by eliminating all coconut from my diet, and this seems to have worked. If I eat anything coconut like coconut
milk or coconut water I start to have some eczema problems in the following days. This was a tricky one to figure out
because like the cat and dog allegy, there is a delayed reaction and the symptoms aren&amp;#39;t so severe right away that
it forces me to notice the link in an obvious way.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I Conquered Eczema after 30 Years of Itchy Skin, And You Can Too</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2019/02/03/i-conquered-eczema-after-30-years-of-itchy-skin-and-you-can-too.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2019/02/03/i-conquered-eczema-after-30-years-of-itchy-skin-and-you-can-too.html</id>
    <published>2019-02-03T18:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-03T18:43:23-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Part 1: Genetics and (Mis)Diagnosis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the National Eczema Foundation, 30 million Americans are afflicted with the itchy, red, blistery skin
condition medically referred to as atopic dermatitis, but better known as eczema. Eczema affects people of all races,
ages, and gender. While it&amp;#39;s not typically a life threatening condition, it can impair quality of life for its sufferers
with a great deal of discomfort and social anxiety. As a life-long sufferer of eczema, I&amp;#39;ve dealt with days where
flare-ups on my hands that were so painful that I&amp;#39;ve had to use sick days from my office job on the computer. I can&amp;#39;t
even imagine what an impairment this condition could become in trades requiring more intense physical labor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;ve landed on this page, chances are you want to learn more about this condition. What I&amp;#39;m going to share in this
series of blog posts is my findings on how to manage eczema, which I hope you will find useful too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Is it eczema or a single episode of dermatitis?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had eczema since I was 5 years old, beginning as two itchy, dry patches of skin on the inner bend of my arms.
The first few times my mom took me to the family doctor, I was given a cream to apply to it and told not to
scratch. Scratching avoidance never seemed to make a difference for me - I would get the rash no matter how hard
I resisted the itching. As a patient, being told not to scratch is upsetting because it can feel like you&amp;#39;re being
blamed for making it worse even though you know that has little to do with the cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a kid most of the time I would just put up with the discomfort and accepted it as part of life. I thought
maybe it was just something everybody deals with, especially during the winter in Chicago. I remember in high school
one day a classmate sitting next to me saw me roll up my sleeve and start scratching the inflamed, dry flakes on my arm.
&amp;quot;You really need to put moisturizer on that!&amp;quot; she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steroid medication always made the skin heal up for a while, but it wouldn&amp;#39;t be long before the problem would
return. I would go back to the doctor on occasion during times when the itching would become unbearable. When I was
a teen we started seeing a new family doctor and every time he would see my rashes on my arm or hands he would say
&amp;quot;That&amp;#39;s contact dermatitis!&amp;quot;, prescribe the same steroid cream, and the cycle continued. It wasn&amp;#39;t until we got the
Internet in my home that I Alta Vista&amp;#39;ed (because Google wasn&amp;#39;t a thing yet) my symptoms and found websites full of
information about this skin problem. For the first time I had an answer as to why I kept getting itchy, flaky, red
rashes in the same spots on my skin - it was eczema and the Internet was full of stories similar to mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the episodic nature of our healthcare delivery system causes people with non-life threatening chronic
problems like this to fall through the cracks until the situation gets severe. After a little over 10 years of doctor
visits, not once was I ever diagnosed with &amp;quot;eczema&amp;quot;. It seems typical for the run of the mill family doctor to treat
each flare-up of eczema as an isolated case of skin irritation, and miss the bigger picture. Your doctor probably
doesn&amp;#39;t live with this condition, and isn&amp;#39;t there with you all day to take note of the lifestyle related things you do
which could be making your eczema better or worse. He just knows that the prescribing drugs will work well enough to
mask the symptoms and send you on your way for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Medications may be useful for suppressing an eczema flare-up, but repeatedly taking this approach has diminishing
returns. Steroid medications like triamcinolone are often the first line of treatment, but they can be hard on your
body. Long term use can lead to the thinning of your skin. Injections of that medication can lead to harmful
side effects like cataracts. Over time they may even become less effective and your condition will worsen. Given that,
why not try to eliminate the cause rather than the symptoms?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my experience I&amp;#39;ve learned that lifestyle factors are influential in managing eczema. Doctors aren&amp;#39;t so well
coordinated in educating you on this lifestyle angle because they can only base their decisions based on the information
they&amp;#39;ve read in established medical journals, which is limited. It takes a lot of experimentation and observation to
figure out the triggers for your particular case. Only you are in the best position to figure out what works for you,
which may vary from person to person. If you are successful, you will save yourself a great deal of discomfort,
expenses, and the harmful long term side effects of prescription medication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Eczema and genetics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is definitely a genetic component to eczema. Some of the medical sites I&amp;#39;ve visited cite one of the root
causes as the &lt;a href="https://ghr.nlm.nih.gov/condition/atopic-dermatitis#genes"&gt;FLG gene&lt;/a&gt;, which helps your body create
certain proteins that waterproof the skin, thereby retaining moisture and keeping out substances that can cause
irritation. People with a corrupted FLG gene do not produce this protein correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I learned more about this condition, I began to see links to my mother&amp;#39;s health. My mom worked in the hospital
as a lab tech and often had trouble with dermatitis on her hands. She would constantly use moisturizers and blamed
the irritation on latex gloves. However, she would sometimes get more extensive rashes and go to the doctor
for creams and sometimes shots to subdue the discomfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on I would have conversations with my mom about my grandmother, who passed away in the Philippines long before
I was born. I learned that my grandmother also dealt with the discomforts of eczema, but on the back of her ankles.
Given this information, it became apparent that my case eczema was a token of the genetic lottery from my mother&amp;#39;s side
of the family. My dad and his parents did not have any such skin problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The immune system&amp;#39;s role in eczema&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although science offers some clues, I don&amp;#39;t think medical research fully understands the mechanics of what causes full
blown eczema. It&amp;#39;s not just that some eczema suffers lack certain proteins in the skin. There is also an immune system
component. A lot of medical research into eczema revolves around overactive immune system response, which causes the
inflammation in the skin that leads to rashes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I subscribe to the idea that because an eczema suffer&amp;#39;s skin may be more porous, environmental irritants are more likely
to get through the outer barriers and trigger the immune system to cause inflammation. This may be why so many doctors
treat chronic eczema like they would a standard case of contact dermatitis (skin irritation/allergy) - because the
body&amp;#39;s mechanisms in causing both kinds of rashes is the same. It&amp;#39;s just that a person with the chronic illness is much
more sensitive to allergens and gets triggered more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stubborn cases of chronic eczema could have multiple triggers, including a combination of allergens and pathogens. The
porus skin of someone with the eczema gene is more susceptible to stealthy bacterial or fungal infections that produce
eczema-like rashes. In such cases, taking a medication like fluconazole in combination with other medication can
provide a great deal of relief and stomp out a persistent flare-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href="2019-02-03-three-allergic-triggers-that-can-cause-eczema.html"&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; of this series, I go into more detail about the allergy and pathogenic factors causing eczema. If you like
this blog series and want to add to the discussion, please leave your feedback on the Disqus board below.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Node on Ruby 2.5.0 (Debian Stretch) Docker Container</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/03/05/how-to-install-node-on-ruby-5-debian-stretch-docker-container.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/03/05/how-to-install-node-on-ruby-5-debian-stretch-docker-container.html</id>
    <published>2018-03-05T18:55:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-05T22:35:41-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another Ruby version, another curveball. Node is no longer in the default package repository for Debian, so you have
to manually add it. Here&amp;#39;s how I got my Dockerfile to run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Dockerfile
FROM ruby:2.5.0
RUN apt-get update
RUN curl -sL https://deb.nodesource.com/setup_9.x | bash -
RUN apt-get install -y nodejs
RUN apt-get install -y npm
RUN npm install yarn -g

CMD mkdir /app
WORKDIR /app
COPY Gemfile /app
COPY Gemfile.lock /app

RUN gem install bundler -v 1.16.1
RUN bundle install

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Install Twitter Bootstrap into a Webpack/React.js Application</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2018/01/30/how-to-install-twitter-bootstrap-into-webpack-react-application.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2018/01/30/how-to-install-twitter-bootstrap-into-webpack-react-application.html</id>
    <published>2018-01-30T18:55:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-31T00:25:59-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Installing Twitter Bootstrap into my React.js application took more effort that I would have liked. There were several
problems I ran into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Bootstrap v3.3.7 fails&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bootstrap 4 is only beta, but it looks like I&amp;#39;m going to have to use it. I had all sorts of problems getting the
includes and dependencies to work with v3.3.7, such as this inability to resolve fonts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ERROR in ./node_modules/css-loader!./node_modules/postcss-loader/lib?{}!./node_modules/sass-loader/lib/loader.js!./stylesheets/style.scss
Module not found: Error: Can&amp;#39;t resolve &amp;#39;../fonts/bootstrap/glyphicons-halflings-regular.eot&amp;#39; in &amp;#39;/Users/wkotzan/Development/momo-scans-frontend/stylesheets&amp;#39;
 @ ./node_modules/css-loader!./node_modules/postcss-loader/lib?{}!./node_modules/sass-loader/lib/loader.js!./stylesheets/style.scss 7:4360-4422 7:4453-4515
 @ ./stylesheets/style.scss
 @ ./js/App.jsx
 @ multi (webpack)-dev-server/client?http://localhost:8080 ./js/App.jsx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could probably troubleshoot some more, but not worth the effort given that Bootstrap 3.3.7 will probably be
obsolete very soon. So onto v4.0.0....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;jQuery problems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you need to get the Javascript dependencies within Bootstrap working. I have the following at the top of my
&lt;code&gt;App.jsx&lt;/code&gt; application file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="javascript"&gt;import &amp;#39;bootstrap&amp;#39;;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I started getting a browser error that the jQuery dependency could not be found and my application page
wouldn&amp;#39;t render. I had to fix this by doing a &lt;code&gt;yarn add jquery&lt;/code&gt; and then adding the following to my Webpack config
file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="javascript"&gt;const webpack = require(&amp;#39;webpack&amp;#39;);

...

  plugins: [
    new webpack.ProvidePlugin({
      $: &amp;#39;jquery&amp;#39;,
      jQuery: &amp;#39;jquery&amp;#39;
    })
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes the JQuery references in Bootstrap universally available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Getting the styles to work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the styles to wor, I had to add this line to my master &lt;code&gt;style.scss&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="scss"&gt;@import &amp;quot;~bootstrap/scss/bootstrap&amp;quot;;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I had to add the following processing plugins to my Webpack config file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="javascript"&gt;  module: {
    rules: [
      {
        test: /\.scss?$/,
        use: [
          { loader: &amp;quot;style-loader&amp;quot; },
          { loader: &amp;quot;css-loader&amp;quot; },
          {
            loader: &amp;quot;postcss-loader&amp;quot;,
            options: {
              plugins: function() {
                return [
                  require(&amp;#39;precss&amp;#39;),
                  require(&amp;#39;autoprefixer&amp;#39;)
                ]
              }
            }
          },
          { loader: &amp;quot;sass-loader&amp;quot; }
        ]
      },
    ]
  },

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Final webpack.config.js&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s my complete Webpack config file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="javascript"&gt;const path = require(&amp;#39;path&amp;#39;);
const webpack = require(&amp;#39;webpack&amp;#39;);

module.exports = {
  context: __dirname,
  entry: &amp;quot;./js/App.jsx&amp;quot;,
  watch: true,
  devtool: &amp;quot;cheap-eval-source-map&amp;quot;,
  output: {
    path: path.resolve(__dirname, &amp;#39;dist&amp;#39;),
    filename: &amp;#39;bundle.js&amp;#39;
  },
  devServer: {
    publicPath: &amp;#39;/dist/&amp;#39;,
    historyApiFallback: true
  },
  resolve: {
    extensions: [&amp;#39;.js&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;.jsx&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;.json&amp;#39;]
  },
  stats: {
    colors: true,
    reasons: true
  },
  module: {
    rules: [
      {
        test: /\.scss?$/,
        use: [
          { loader: &amp;quot;style-loader&amp;quot; },
          { loader: &amp;quot;css-loader&amp;quot; },
          {
            loader: &amp;quot;postcss-loader&amp;quot;,
            options: {
              plugins: function() {
                return [
                  require(&amp;#39;precss&amp;#39;),
                  require(&amp;#39;autoprefixer&amp;#39;)
                ]
              }
            }
          },
          { loader: &amp;quot;sass-loader&amp;quot; }
        ]
      },
      { test: /\.jsx?$/, use: &amp;#39;babel-loader&amp;#39; }
    ]
  },
  plugins: [
    new webpack.ProvidePlugin({
      $: &amp;#39;jquery&amp;#39;,
      jQuery: &amp;#39;jquery&amp;#39;
    })
  ]
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information source: &lt;a href="https://getbootstrap.com/docs/4.0/getting-started/webpack/"&gt;TWBS documentation&lt;/a&gt;, Stack Overflow&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
