<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2017-09-05T19:55:00-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Shut Down of MomentumStockScans.com and USTreasuryYieldCurve.com</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/09/05/shutting-down-momo-scans-and-ustreasurycurve.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/09/05/shutting-down-momo-scans-and-ustreasurycurve.html</id>
    <published>2017-09-05T19:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-05T22:18:16-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am temporarily shutting down my websites momentumstockscans.com and ustreasuryyieldcurve.com. I initially thought
these websites would generate sufficient traffic to be self-sustainable from ad revenue, but at the moment they
are unprofitable. Both websites require their own databases and run via Docker containers hosted on AWS, which gets
costly. I will put the websites back up as they were once I find a more cost effective hosting solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why Bitcoin Will Fail for SHTF</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/31/bitcoin-will-fail-for-shtf.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/31/bitcoin-will-fail-for-shtf.html</id>
    <published>2017-07-31T19:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-08-03T23:46:16-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jjAC446ZAaE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A single Bitcoin today sells more than an ounce of gold — but is it a good currency for SHTF? A lot of people are
hoarding Bitcoin these days because they think it is a way to guard themselves against the demise of the US dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To many people, Bitcoin represents a way to fight back against the banking cartel. They don’t think the government
can regulate it. It sounds like a currency by and for the people. However, as someone who works in the technology
field I see some some technological reasons to think that holding Bitcoin as a long term defensive asset is a bad idea.
Some of the perceived advantages are not as strong as the layperson may believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bitcoin is not anonymous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very basis of how Bitcoin works is the blockchain, meaning that every Bitcoin transaction ever made is recorded
in a public ledger. While the blockchain may be hard to read, theoretically anyone with a sophisticated enough computing
power and some detective work can trace a particular transaction to its origin by looking at all of the addresses on the
ledger. It’s unlike cash in which no record is kept once it’s been moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The government can find indirect ways of regulating Bitcoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government can find ways to regulate the use of Bitcoin by implement rules making it difficult to use. Already, the
IRS classifies Bitcoin as an asset and not a currency, meaning that you have to pay capital gains taxes if your Bitcoin
appreciates in value and you sell it for a profit. This means that in the lens of the financial world, Bitcoin has more
in common with a stock certificate than a US dollar. The Bitcoin nodes and exchanges are also a vulnerable to
regulation. To convert dollars into Bitcoin and back you need to use an exchange. If they got serious about controlling
Bitcoin, the regulators could impose taxes or fees on the use of exchanges, or go after the people running the nodes
that process the Bitcoin ledger. Recently the engineers running the Bitcoin project implemented an update to the
blockchain called SegWit, which was implemented through the exchanges. This is a testament to the fact that there are
bottlenecks in the Bitcoin ecosystem that can be controlled by a regulatory authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mining nodes in the infrastructure is a vulnerability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/2017/03/plan-save-blockchain-democracy-bitcoins-civil-war/"&gt;Miners are needed to process the transactions.&lt;/a&gt; This
can come under attack, or without enough infrastructure could run very slow. Right now it could take up to hours for a
Bitcoin transaction to make its way through the ledger. This is a huge impediment when using Bitcoin for commerce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technological breakthrough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moore’s Law is currently broke for the moment, meaning that over the past several years chip manufacturers have been
having a harder time making processors more powerful at the tepid pace that they have been for the last 20 years. But
let’s say Moore’s Law catches up - if we have a hardware technology breakthrough - what could that mean for
cryptocurrencies like bitcoin? Would a quantum computer be able to break the encryption and crack the digital
signatures by brute force? If that occurs then anyone’s Bitcoin account could be at risk of getting hacked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Old fashioned manipulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The limited supply of Bitcoins may solve the inflationary problems of money printing, but it’s vulnerable to manipulation through supply and demand - just like a stock price.
        - Market cap is only $42B, but some publicly traded companies have a market cap much higher. Apple has a market cap of $800B. Someone with enough money can control the price of Bitcoin much like a high frequency trader can control the short term price of a stock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Final Word&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is a virtual asset, but it’s a commodity just like any other kind of financial asset. You can make money from
speculation in it, but it’s worth as a store of value in an economic or societal disaster is questionable. Peppers who
are buying Bitcoin may be misguided. I know stocks better, so I’d rather use my speculative money in the stock market.
For ecological disasters, I think it’s better to hold physical assets such as gold, silver, or even commodity goods
that can be traded because those will have a use if the Internet goes down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superinflation might be the best reason to hold Bitcoin. However, I believe the market has already priced this in
because of the rapidly rising price action it&amp;#39;s seen over the last several years. It looks like a parabolic stock
chart, and many of Bitcoin&amp;#39;s proponents speak of it like an investment that can never fail. Sounds like bubble talk to
me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I think cryptocurrencies are unreliable long term holdings as an economic, political, or natural disaster
hedges, there could be other uses for them. I like some of the ideas driving Ethereum, because is has it has a purpose
in running distributed applications and contracts. But that’s for another video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a daily list of great stock trading ideas, check out MomentumStockScans.com, follow me on Twitter -
and don’t forget to like the video and subscribe to my channel. See you next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to Download Videos from Youtube and Save Them on Your Hard Drive</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/27/how-to-download-youtube-videos-to-your-hard-drive.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/27/how-to-download-youtube-videos-to-your-hard-drive.html</id>
    <published>2017-07-27T19:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-27T22:22:35-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately Youtube has been more aggressive in taking down political videos as part of their campaign against &amp;quot;fake news&amp;quot; and alleged &amp;quot;hate speech&amp;quot;. However, many users are angered by Youtube&amp;#39;s unclear and seemingly arbitrary policy for removing videos, accusing Youtube&amp;#39;s management of censoring videos based on the political opinions they present. As someone who is against the censorship of free speech, I created this video to help viewers of Youtube save the content of their favorite creators. By downloading videos and saving them, you will still have access to them after Youtube removes them and help maintain their circulation in the public sphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J73aV3BWMj4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Interviewing Tip - 3 Step Process fo Writing a Good Cover Letter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/17/interviewing-tip-3-step-process-to-a-good-cover-letter.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/17/interviewing-tip-3-step-process-to-a-good-cover-letter.html</id>
    <published>2017-07-17T19:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-18T15:18:22-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cover letters are important! After going through a pile of resumes, they can all start to look the same. Most job
applicants for a particular position will have work histories in some business-y job doing similar job titles, give or
take a few years difference in experience. The one chance you have to stand out and make &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; application stand out
is through a well written cover letter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve come up with a simple 3-step formula for making your cover letter concise and make your background stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduce yourself - tell them who you are and what you&amp;#39;re looking for. You can even say what exactly it was
about this particular posting that caught your attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pull out something about the job position and write about how you have relevant experience doing that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Call to action. This is something I learned to consciously do from Youtube.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s look at an example hypothetical job posting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a Senior Ruby Developer to join our existing team. The position is full time and can be remote.
Strong knowledge of Ruby is required. Real world experience building and maintaining Ruby on Rails apps is a must - from UI to APIs. This project will involve being part of a team working on an application used by tens of thousands of customers every day.
Our typical project stack is Ruby, Rails, JavaScript and PostgreSQL. We prefer developers who  embrace new approaches and the craft of software design to solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;#39;s read the same posting again, this time I&amp;#39;m going to highlight key phrases to pull out for crafting a cover
letter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are &lt;span style="color: green; font-weight: bold"&gt;looking for a Senior Ruby Developer&lt;/span&gt; to join our existing team. The position is full time and &lt;span style="color: green; font-weight: bold"&gt;can be remote&lt;/span&gt;.
Strong knowledge of Ruby is required. &lt;span style="color: blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;Real world experience building and maintaining Ruby on Rails apps is a must - from UI to APIs&lt;/span&gt;. This project will involve being part of a team working on an application &lt;span style="color: blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;used by tens of thousands of customers&lt;/span&gt; every day.
Our typical project stack is &lt;span style="color: blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;Ruby, Rails, JavaScript and PostgreSQL&lt;/span&gt;. We prefer developers who embrace new approaches and the craft of software design to solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I color coded accordingly to match steps 1, 2, and 3 of the process I am suggesting. Here&amp;#39;s the cover letter body:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;span style="color: green; font-weight: bold"&gt;an experienced Ruby on Rails developer&lt;/span&gt; looking for &lt;span style="color: green; font-weight: bold"&gt;remote work&lt;/span&gt;.
I enjoy working on a variety of projects, and have been &lt;span style="color: green; font-weight: bold"&gt;taking on remote contracts of late&lt;/span&gt;. At FinCorp, a Chicago-based finance tech company, I worked with an agile team to maintain and build new logic into a Ruby-based accounting system for a &lt;span style="color: blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;$3 billion loan portfolio&lt;/span&gt;.
In other projects, I&amp;#39;ve also written Ruby programs to &lt;span style="color: blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;scrape large amounts of data from financial APIs&lt;/span&gt;. My expertise falls largely into back-end and data management with systems like &lt;span style="color: blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/span&gt;, but I am also familiar with &lt;span style="color: blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;front end including Javascript, JQuery, and React&lt;/span&gt;.
I hope you find my qualifications appealing. I am eager to get to together with a bright team and start some new interesting projects! &lt;span style="color: red; font-weight: bold"&gt;Please reply to this email if you think I’m a good fit for the team!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I start off by saying I&amp;#39;m an experienced Ruby developer looking to work remotely to show that the kind of job I&amp;#39;m looking for
is aligned with the kind of employee they are looking to higher. The job posting stresses they want someone with real world
experience making applications and interfacing APIs. Their website is a busy one with lost of customers. To highlight how I
worked on sizable systems like that, I state that I worked on a large accounting system for $3 billion worth of loans and
also mention my API experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now my weak area for this job search is my lack of resume experience building the front end experience of websites. However,
I try to make up for it by stating the major frameworks I&amp;#39;m familiar with. When applying for a job, it&amp;#39;s okay to fall short
on a bullet point or two if you strongly meet the other requirements they are seeking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I have the call to action by suggesting the reader reply to this email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0985757116/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0985757116&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=winstonkotzan-20&amp;linkId=49527ca8d490f74681ce640c10f22108"&gt;This is Not Your Father&amp;#39;s Job Market: Job Seeking Strategies for Today&amp;#39;s New College Graduates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src="//ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=winstonkotzan-20&amp;l=am2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0985757116" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style="width:120px;height:240px;" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=winstonkotzan-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=0985757116&amp;asins=0985757116&amp;linkId=f280bde1ac5d26e167436aca1ba048ee&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=0066c0&amp;bg_color=ffffff"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Interviewing Tip - Peel the Onion</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/13/interviewing-tip-peel-the-onion.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/13/interviewing-tip-peel-the-onion.html</id>
    <published>2017-07-13T19:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-20T20:47:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m the author of the college student job search guide, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0985757116/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0985757116&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=winstonkotzan-20&amp;amp;linkId=49527ca8d490f74681ce640c10f22108"&gt;This is Not Your Father&amp;#39;s Job Market&lt;/a&gt;,
and right now I&amp;#39;m actively using those job search skills again myself as I look for new technical projects. Something that I
retrospectively caught myself doing today during a phone interview is rambling a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the tricky things about interviewing in general, but in particular with phone interviewing, is that it&amp;#39;s easy to
spill too much information when answering an interview question. So in the call I was on today, I asked the interviewer
about the production stack they are using to run their website. He said that their front-end is very simple-just some
plain Javascript, but in this role I was in I may have an opportunity to help them decide how to build a more up-to-date
front end. I then started talking about my personal experience using React.js and other front end frameworks, and probably
spoke for a good 3 minutes espousing my opinions of the pros and cons of each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a few reasons talking too continuously is bad for interviews:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;#39;t have visual cues as to how the interviewer is reacting. i.e.) the person on the other end of the
line might look bored or disinterested in what you are saying, but since you can&amp;#39;t see it&amp;#39;s difficult to know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You might reveal something compromising or contrary to what the interviewer is looking for. For example, I may have
given the impression in this case that I was biased to React.js. What if this team wanted to use Ember.js?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You might inadvertently come across as a know-it-all. Talking too much on a topic makes it sound like you&amp;#39;re
trying to dominate the conversation. This can easily happen over the phone when only one person can speak at a time.
At worst, your opinions may even conflict with the interviewer&amp;#39;s opinions making you a dislikable candidate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way to fix this is to only give enough information and talk long enough to give what&amp;#39;s needed - it&amp;#39;s like peeling an
onion only one layer at a time. Don&amp;#39;t give away the whole thing at once. If the interviewer is interested in what you
have to say, he&amp;#39;ll probe for more. You can also end each statement you make by affirming with: &amp;quot;Does that adequately
answer the question?&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;Is there any topic you&amp;#39;d like me to talk about some more?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a job search guide full of awesome tips like this, I recommend getting a copy of my book! Link below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0985757116/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0985757116&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=winstonkotzan-20&amp;linkId=49527ca8d490f74681ce640c10f22108"&gt;This is Not Your Father&amp;#39;s Job Market: Job Seeking Strategies for Today&amp;#39;s New College Graduates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src="//ir-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=winstonkotzan-20&amp;l=am2&amp;o=1&amp;a=0985757116" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style="width:120px;height:240px;" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=winstonkotzan-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=0985757116&amp;asins=0985757116&amp;linkId=f280bde1ac5d26e167436aca1ba048ee&amp;show_border=false&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=0066c0&amp;bg_color=ffffff"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Capistrano + Docker could not find an available, non-overlapping IPv4 address pool among the defaults to assign to the network</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2017/07/12/docker-could-not-find-available-ipv4-address.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2017/07/12/docker-could-not-find-available-ipv4-address.html</id>
    <published>2017-07-12T01:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-12T22:03:52-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So on my latest Capistrano deploy to &lt;a href="http://www.momentumstockscans.com"&gt;MomentumStockScans.com&lt;/a&gt;, I received the following
error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo docker-compose up -d
sudo: unable to resolve host ip-172-30-0-194
Creating network &amp;quot;20170713014600_default&amp;quot; with the default driver
ERROR: could not find an available, non-overlapping IPv4 address pool among the defaults to assign to the network
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out every time I was running &lt;code&gt;docker-compose&lt;/code&gt; it created a new bridge network, and &lt;a href="https://github.com/moby/moby/issues/23971"&gt;there&amp;#39;s a limit of 31 networks
on the system&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I did &lt;code&gt;docker network ls&lt;/code&gt;, it gave me a whole list of networks it created. One for each deploy. I cleared them using&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo docker network prune
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was fine! Will add the above command to my Capistrano deploy script.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
